The Power of Uchiha
オレには 別のつながりがある…。
I have different bonds...
兄との 憎しみっていう
つながりがな…。
Bonds of hatred with
my older brother...
いくつもの つながりは…。
Numerous bonds...
己を惑わせ…。
mislead oneself...
もっとも強い願い…。
and weaken
the most important desires...
大切な思いを弱くする…。
and cherished memories.
((いいかげんに
目ぇ覚めたかよ コラ！
Have you finally opened
your eyes...Sasuke?!
サスケ！
うるせえんだよ…。
Shut up.
You don't even have parents
or siblings...
親も兄弟もいねえ テメエに➡
オレの何がわかるってんだよ！
What do you know about me?!
初めから 一人きりだったテメエに➡
You've been alone from the start!
オレの何がわかるってんだ！ あぁ!?
What do you know
about me?! Huh?!
It's having the bond
that makes it painful!
つながりがあるからこそ
苦しいんだ…。
それを失うことが どんなもんか➡
You've no idea what it's like...
to lose that!
お前なんかに わかるか！
You're right.
ホントの親子や兄弟なんて➡
I don't know about having
real parents or siblings...
(確かに オレにはわかんねえ…))
それなら なんで…。
If that's the case, then why...?
Why, Naruto...?
((なんでだ？ ナルト…。
なんで そこまでして
オレなんかに…。
Why do you go so far for me...?
オレにとっちゃ やっとできた
つながりなんだ。
To me, it's a bond...I've finally
been able to establish.
That's why I'll stop you!
(だから オレは…
お前を止めるんだってばよ！))
Why didn't you...
なんで あのとき…。
I can't turn back...
((オレは 後には戻れない。
(だったら そのつながりを
オレは断ち切るまでだ！))
Then I'll just break
that bond!
Why didn't you kill me
back then?!
なんで あのとき
オレを殺さなかった!?
You think that could
break our bond, Sasuke?!
それで断ち切ったつもりかよ！
サスケ!!
ナルト…。
Naruto...
簡単な理由だ。
The reason's simple...
It's not that I couldn't break
the bond with you...
お前とのつながりを
断ち切れなかったんじゃない。
((お前も オレと同じ
万華鏡写輪眼を➡
You're one...
who might be able to use the same
Mangekyo Sharingan as mine...
開眼しうる者だ…。
However, there's a condition.
ただし それには条件がある。
You must kill...
もっとも親しい友を…
殺すことだ。
your closest friend.
That's...!
(そんな…))
It was just irritating to me.
アイツに聞かされた
やり方に従って➡
力を手にするのが
しゃくだっただけだ。
Obtaining power based on
the method he told me.
どういうことだってばよ。
What do you mean?!
お前に説明する必要はない。
It's not necessary
to explain that to you.
What I can say to you is...
ただ お前に言えることは…。
Back then...
あのとき…。
Chidori!
((千鳥！
螺旋丸！
Rasengan!
千鳥！
螺旋丸！
- Rasengan!
- Chidori!
ナルト…。
Naruto...
I...
(オレは…))
あのとき… お前の命は…。
Back then...
You're only alive
because of my passing whim.
オレの気まぐれで助かった
だけだということだ。
《速い…！》
He's fast!
《いつの間に!?》
When did he...?
そういや お前には
火影になるっていう➡
Come to think of it,
wasn't it your dream
to become the Hokage...?
夢があるんじゃなかったか？
オレを追いまわすヒマがあったら
修業でもしてりゃよかったのに。
If you had the time
to be chasing after me,
you should've spent that time
training or something.
なぁ… ナルト。
Right, Naruto?
S-Sasuke...!
サ… サスケ君…。
And so this time around...
だから今度は オレの気まぐれで…。
you'll lose your life...
お前は命を落とすんだぜ…。
because of my passing whim.
No way can a guy who can't
even save one friend...
仲間一人 救えねえヤツが
火影になんてなれるかよ。
become the Hokage.
そうだろ… サスケ。
Isn't that right, Sasuke?
Sasuke!
(サクラ)サスケ君！
その防ぎ方… 正解だったな。
That manner of defense...
was correct.
よし！
All right!
フン！
千鳥 流し！
Chidori Stream!
《全身から千鳥を…》
He's unleashing Chidori
from his entire body...!
((ごめん ナルト…。
Sorry, Naruto...
(サクラ)少し 待たせることに
なっちゃうけど…。
You'll have to wait a while...
今度は きっと…。
Next time, I promise...
(足手まといには ならないから！))
I won't be a burden.
《サクラ : サスケ君は…。
I'll stop Sasuke...
私の力で止める！》
with my own power!
ハッ…。
Those eyes.
This guy's bad news.
《あの目 コイツ やばいな…》
あぁっ…。
Captain Yamato!
ヤマト隊長！
That manner of defense...
その防ぎ方…。
あぁっ…。
was a mistake.
失敗だったな。
This Snake Sword of mine
is somewhat special, you see.
オレの草薙の剣は 少し特別でな。
ガード不可ってヤツだ。
It's impossible to guard.
《体が痺れる…。
My body is getting numb...
これは
刃に千鳥を流しているのか？
This is...
Is he sending a Chidori
through the blade...?
I get it... It paralyzes you
with numbness after cutting...
そうか… それで 切れ味を➡
極端に上げたうえに➡
斬りつけたあと 痺れで動きを…》
on top of increasing the cutting quality
to the extreme...
ん？
フッ…。
どうやら おもしろいことに
なっているようだ。
It appears...
things have gotten interesting.
クッ… うっ…。
うぅっ…。
うっ…。
(九尾)フフフ… チャンスだぞ。
Now's your chance, Naruto...
(九尾)ナルトよ…。
Show him...our...
(九尾)ワシと お前の力を➡
powers.
見せつけてやれ。
(九尾)どうした？
What's the matter...?
Why do you hesitate...?
(九尾)何を躊躇している？
(九尾)ワシの力が必要なのだろう？
You need my power, don't you?
(九尾)さぁ…。
Now then...
Who do you want to kill...?
誰を殺したい？
Don't...come out anymore!
もう… テメエは出てくんな！
何を怖がる？
What're you afraid of?
うるせえ！
Shut up...!
オレには もう
お前の力なんか必要ねえ！
I don't need anything like
your power anymore!
フフフフ…。
ハハハハ…！
今まで 事あるごとに
力を貸せとぬかしたのは➡
Who was the one
who had the nerve...
to ask for my help
at every opportunity?
どこのどいつだ…？
わかっているはずだぞ。
You should know that you can't
do anything on your own.
お前は 一人では何もできん。
(九尾)封印を完全に解け！
Break the Seal completely!
そうすれば お前に
すべての力を託してやる！
I'll grant you all of my powers
if you do.
うせろ！
Get lost!
おぉっ… お前は…。
You...
そうか… うちはの者か！
I see...
So you're an Uchiha...
よく ここまで成長したものだ。
My, how you've grown...
What're you doing here...?
どうして お前が…。
今なら見える…
これが お前の未知の力だったか。
I can see it now...
So this is
your unknown power, huh...?
まさか お前の中に
こんなものがいたとはな…。
Who would've thought...
you'd have something like this
inside of you...
ナルトの中のワシが
見えるまでになるとはな。
To think you'd become able
to see me within Naruto...
忌まわしき その写輪眼…。
That dreadful Sharingan...
So that's the power of
the cursed clan, huh?
呪われた一族の力というわけか。
どうやら 写輪眼を見るのは
初めてではないらしいな。
It seems this isn't the first time
you've seen the Sharingan.
Then...
なら… お前が九尾の妖狐か。
you must be
the Nine-Tailed Fox, huh...?
その瞳力と
ワシ以上に まがまがしいチャクラ。
That vision, and Chakra
more ominous than mine...
かつての
うちは マダラと同じだな。
It's just like...
the Madara Uchiha
from olden times...
《うちは…》
Uchiha...
知るかよ…。
Hell if I know...that person.
そんなヤツ…。
(九尾)まさか ワシの力を
抑え込むまでとはな。
I never thought...
you would go so far as
to suppress my power...
最後になるかもしれんが
ひとつ 言っておく。
This might be the end...
But let me tell you...one thing...
Don't...kill...Naruto...
ナルトは 殺すな…。
後悔することに…。
You'll...
regret...it...
フン！
Wood Style: Domed Wall!
木遁 木錠壁！
サスケ…。
Sasuke...
今日は サスケ君とお兄さんが
仲がよかった時代を振り返るわ！
昔から天才と呼ばれていたイタチ。
兄の陰に隠れて
目立たなかったサスケ君。
周りの人たちはイタチにばかり
期待をかけていたようだけど➡
当のイタチは 何かと
サスケ君の世話を焼いていたみたい。
((イタチ : 許せ サスケ…。
Looks like it's meaningless...
(また今度だ。
イテッ！))
to try and convince
Sasuke further than this.
Captain Yamato...
(サクラ)サスケ君は
お兄さんに追いつきたくて➡
必死に がんばっていたのね。
でも…。
((兄さん… なんて遠いんだ。
オレが疎ましいか？
そんなふうには…。
お前の超えるべき壁として➡
オレは
お前とともに あり続けるのさ。
(たとえ 憎まれようともな…))
(サクラ)まさか
そんなイタチの優しい顔が➡
すべて演技だったなんて…。
(サクラ)そして あの事件以来➡
イタチは サスケ君にとって➡
倒すべき宿敵となったの。